<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organisation Structure on Amit Kumar</title>
    <link>https://toamitkumar.in/tags/organisation-structure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organisation Structure on Amit Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://toamitkumar.in/tags/organisation-structure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guardrail-ed Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://toamitkumar.in/2021/01/30/guardrail-ed-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://toamitkumar.in/2021/01/30/guardrail-ed-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t written much in recent years, at least not through blog posts. I thought 2021, would be a good time to start penning some of my thoughts &amp;amp; learnings I have had in the recent past years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Team formation, functioning, reporting are the most common challenges every organisation have. Lately, I have been involved in discussions related to Team Autonomy. Hence, this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autonomy&#34;&gt;Autonomy&lt;/a&gt; has different meaning based on context: political, medical, HR, organisation. Narrowing our focus to an Organisation, it has a wide spectrum from highly-organised (CMM levels or SixSigmas) to an Anarchical setup (a budding startup). I have never been a fan of being at the edge of the spectrum, it has its own consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agility and Component Driven Development</title>
      <link>https://toamitkumar.in/2012/05/30/guardrail-ed-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://toamitkumar.in/2012/05/30/guardrail-ed-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile development has become the backbone of modern software development process. In a nutshell, it can be defined as - &lt;strong&gt;iterative, self-evolving incremental development that demands high collaboration and flexibility to change&lt;/strong&gt;. Component driven development on the other hand augments to building reusable and testable components that be plugged together to form application foundation for delivering business functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our current engagement with Firm Account, they have started providing IT tools/solutions to their clients supplementing the strategic solutions they have been providing so far. They wanted to deliver the solution with rapid-prototyping and rapid-delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
